

melnykroman925@gmail.com

Khrystynivka, Ukraine

# Melnyk Roman

### **Profile**

I am a skilled **mobile & web developer** with 6 years of experience in designing and implementing innovative web applications.

I provide advanced web solutions using ReactJs/NextJS, Laravel,

MongoDB/PostgreSQL & Tailwind, SCSS technologies and build mobile app with Native Android & IOS and ReactNative & Flutter.

## **Employment History**

#### Junior Mobile Developer at INTETICS INC, Lviv

09/2016-03/2019

- Developed mobile-friendly user interfaces that increased mobile traffic by 25%
- Developed and executed mobile application testing to ensure that the software runs flawlessly on different mobile platforms

# Frontend, Backend Developer at SIGMA SOFTWARE GROUP, Lviv

04/2019-01/2024

- Integrated mobile applications with backend services, resulting in a 40% increase in app functionality and a 25% increase in user engagement.
- Implemented security and data protection measures, resulting in a 50% decrease in security breaches and a 20% increase in user trust.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define and ship new features, resulting in a 30% increase in app downloads and a 15% increase in revenue.

### Education

Bachelor of Computer Science (BCompSc), Lviv Polytechnic National University, Lviv

02/2012-06/2016

### Skills

Laravel	5/5
PHP	5/5
ReactJS	5/5
NextJS	4/5
Android	5/5
IOS	5/5
ReactNative	
Flutter	4/5
CSS	5/5
Tailwind	4/5
SCSS	4/5

### Languages

English ...... Highly proficient